Robin Mills

400 N First St #311 San Jose, CA 95112 United States of America

PHONE

Home: +1 (408) 288 7673 Cell: +1 (408) 394 1534

EMAIL

robin@clanmills.com

WEB

http://clanmills.com

DOCUMENT REVISION

October 2010

AVAILABILITY

December 2010

Profile

I am a software engineer. I've been involved with computer software since school. I've worked on many different technologies including:

Development of Compilers and Interpreters

Computer Graphics

Build Engineering. Documentation. Scripting.

Windows, Mac, Linux/Unix, Embedded & Mobile.

Computer Aided Design

Rapid Prototyping and Demonstration Products.

My strongest asset is explaining things and I've lost count of the folks who've said: "When you explain things, it always sounds so simple." My reply: "Thank You. It works because it is simple!".

Experience

CONTRACT ENGINEER, ADOBE SYSTEMS INCORPORATED, SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA, 5/2010 - 11/2011

Acrobat Installer Engineer. Replaced the compression engine in the Mac and Windows installers for Acrobat X. Code and package signing, build engineering infrastructure. Tools: C++, DevStudio, XCode, 7z, python, packagemaker, bash and ant.

CONTRACT ENGINEER, NOVARIANT INCORPORATED, FREMONT, CALIFORNIA, 9/2008 - 12/2009

All purpose engineer for the company's embedded steering controller. This is a robot to drive a farm tractor. We've shipped this on both Windows/CE and Linux/Embedded. I initially ported the core code (I million lines of Linux C++) to Windows. I've also worked on the UI (Java and JavaScript), the Database (SQLite), installers and web server. Tools: Dev Studio, Eclipse, bash, perl, Firebug, VirtualBox.

SENIOR COMPUTER SCIENTIST, ADOBE SYSTEMS, SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA. 1998-2007

I joined the company in England as a Consulting Engineer (OEM support for PostScript). In 2000 I was invited to relocate to San Jose, CA as a Project Lead Engineer in the Print Technology Group. I also spent several years in Core Technology working on ExtendScript - the company's JavaScript interpreter. I gave presentations at the Adobe Tech Summit (engineering conference). Almost all code at Adobe is developed for Windows and Apple and often Linux.

DIRECTOR, ROBIN MILLS SOFTWARE CONSULTANCY

I had my own business for 4 years and had a very successful 3 year contract with AGFA in Antwerp, Belgium to develop AgfaScript - a cross-platform PostScript interpreter (Solaris, AIX and Windows)

OPEN SOURCE AND OTHER ACTIVITY

I contribute to three open-source projects involving exif photograhic meta data: exiv2 (C++ exif library), pyexiv2 (python wrapper for exiv2) and Phatch for which I developed the GeoTag Action. Frequent contributor to forums.macosxhints.com. and cocoaforum.com. Moderator on forum.whatismyip.com (a network forum). Fit & healthy and qualified/ran in the Boston Marathon in 2006. Happily married. European Citizen and US resident (green card).

Skills

I've written and fixed a lot of code. I'm quick at learning new technologies and reading and understanding other people's code. I rank my skill set at:

Very C++, C and JavaScript Dev Studio, XCode

Strong Windows, MacOS-X Presentations, Training Courses, Public Speaking

Win32 and MFC Prototyping and demonstrations

Strong Build Engineering Cocoa/ObjC/ObjC++

Scripting Perl and Python

Linux Web technologies (HTML, CSS, HTTP, CGI, ASP)

Good Writing documentation | Java and Eclipse

Education

University of Glasgow, Scotland. B Sc with First Class Honors in Engineering.

Referrals (email/phone numbers provided on request)

Dennis Connor Director of Development, Novariant Incorporated, Fremont CA.

Richard Dermer Senior Computer Scientist, Adobe Systems Incorporated, Seattle WA.

Senior Computer Scientist, Adobe Systems Incorporated, San Jose CA.